Software Engineer | Eduardo Villasenor

(831)206-5546 | <u>eduardovillasenor1992@gmail.com</u> linkedin.com/in/eduardo-villasenor | https://github.com/EdwardVilla0

Summary

Software Engineer with experience in different fields of tech such as Web Development, QA Engineer and Support Tech. Dedicated to learning the industries leading technological trends and adapting them to early innovations.

Technologies/Technical Skills

JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, Node.js, SQL, Java, C++, Agile Development cycle, Jira, Zendesk, Confluence.

Professional Experience

Digital Schools, Salinas CA

Quality Assurance Engineer, January 2019 - May 2020

- Reviewed TypeScript and SQL code to pinpoint root cause of issue.
- Helped to design a user interface for easier navigation.
- Created test cases, documented and reported issues in newly developed code using Jira.
- Assisted with continued improvement in the software and performance testing process.

Digital Schools, Salinas CA

Support Tech II, July 2018 - May 2020

- Troubleshoot issues reported by clients on zendesk in order for a more streamlike user interface experience.
- Implement new user data into the servers in order to use the software.
- Created reports for clients from a relational database using SQL queries to present to State and Federal
 agencies.
- Updated and maintained databases for school districts throughout California.

North County Recreation and Park District, Castroville CA

Intern, January 2018 - May 2018

- Created a mobile application that would keep track of students checking into the facility in order to allocate funding from the state.
- Updated and maintained the organization's website for event planning.

Heaven on Earth Furniture, Salinas

Web Developer/Technology Consultant, January 2011 - July 2018

- Created and updated products on the company's website when new inventory would be released and/or available.
- Help with the transition from paper records of finance to Quickbooks accounting software.
- Provide training and support to the sales team when new technology was adopted.

Education

BS, Software Engineering - May 2018
California State University Monterey Bay, Seaside CA
AA, Software Engineering - May 2016
Hartnell College, Salinas CA